<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Arina Igumenshcheva</title>
    <link>http://33eyes.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Arina Igumenshcheva</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 12:19:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://33eyes.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphConnect NYC 2018</title>
      <link>http://33eyes.github.io/posts/graphconnect-nyc-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 12:19:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://33eyes.github.io/posts/graphconnect-nyc-2018/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve attended the GraphConnect conference in NYC. I had a great time at the conference, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d share my experience, along with a brief intro to graph concepts and technologies.
About the conference Day 1: Sessions  Keynote speeches Talks about applications of graph databases and graph analytics across a wide gamut of industries, including:  Fraud detection Healthcare IT Medical and scientific research Web development AI and ML GDPR compliance Master data management Identity and access management HR Finance And anything that relies on recommender engines  Neo4j-led sessions covering product features, use cases and new releases  2018 update highlights:  Neo4j Bloom: a visual graph exploration application Spatial features in Neo4j Temporal date types Graph algorithms library An updated APOC library Neo4j Morpheus: combines graph and relational table functionalities into one application   2018 Graphie Awards: a recognition of companies and graph community members for their contributions to the graph tech community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Wikipedia clickstream</title>
      <link>http://33eyes.github.io/posts/wiki-project-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 10:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://33eyes.github.io/posts/wiki-project-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I want to learn about something, I google it, and sooner or later I end up on Wikipedia. And so do millions of other people, in many different languages. Wikipedia is a vast repository of knowledge organized into interlinked articles, and there are lots of ways to navigate through it as we learn. Whenever we browse Wikipedia, we learn and gather information, so perhaps our browsing behavior tendencies on Wikipedia can tell us something about how we learn on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First week at Metis</title>
      <link>http://33eyes.github.io/posts/first-week-at-metis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 10:20:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://33eyes.github.io/posts/first-week-at-metis/</guid>
      <description>My first week at Metis has just breezed by. While I am not new to data analytics and statistics, I am new to data science and Python. For me, this past week has been a mix of a few things old and familiar, and a lot of things new and surprising. We&amp;rsquo;ve covered lots of introductory grounds on Git and GitHub, pair programming, Pandas, complexity, Matplotlib, command line basics, Seaborn, and, of course, many more Python topics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>